Guide to the Mary McCarthy Papers, circa 1915-2013 (bulk 1960-1989)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES I: WRITINGS
  - Notes and Notebooks of McCarthy
    - Notebook — The Stones of Florence (Folder 327.7)
    - Notebook — English Gothic (Folder 328.1)
    - Notes — Miscellaneous (Folder 328.2)
    - Notebook — Miscellaneous (Folder 328.3)
    - Notebook — Ideas and the Novel (Folder 328.4)
    - Notebook — The Gothic (Folder 328.5)
    - Notebook — Miscellaneous, circa 1979 (Folder 328.6)
    - Notebook — [France and Vietnam] (Folder 328.7)
    - Notebook — Miscellaneous (Folder 328.12)
    - Notebook — Miscellaneous (Folder 328.13)
    - Notebook — Miscellaneous (Folder 362.)
    - Notebook — Notes for Autobiography (Folder 328.14)
  - Contributions to Others' Works by McCarthy
    - Miscellaneous
      - Exhibition catalogs — Scott and Fowles Galleries, NY, 1948, 1949, 1952; (3) (Folder 88.1)
      - Preface to The Guerillas, by Monique Wittig — typescript draft [fragment], 1971 (Folder 88.2)
      - Essay for Lebenstein '75 — typescript draft, Manuscript notes, and correspondence, 1972 (Folder 88.3)
      - Lebenstein '75 — see also oversized section for booklet
      - "Looking Back on 'Locos'" — typescript variants with manuscript notes (Folder 88.4)
      - "Looking Back on 'Locos'" — correspondence (Folder 88.5)
      - Alfau. Locos: A Comedy of Gestures, Elmwood Park, IL, Dalkey Archive Press, — galley proof, 1988 (Folders 88.6 - 88.8)
      - "Looking Back ...," The New York Review of Books — galleys of article, 1988 (Folder 88.9)
      - "Looking Back ...," The New York Review of Books — printed article, 22 December 1988 (Folder 88.10)
      - "Two Discoveries": [Locos and Village Chronicle], The Nation — printed article, 27 June 1936 (Folder 88.11)
      - Preface to Niccolò Tucci, The Rain Came Last, New Directions, NY — manuscript notes, typescript variants, 1990 (Folder 88.12)
      - The Worlds of Fiction (1964) — typescript draft of preface with correspondence, 1962 (Folder 91.12)
      - The Worlds of Fiction — See also McCarthy typescript draft of "The Unspoiled Reaction" in folder 83.7.
    - Chiaromonte, Nicola
      - Memorial volume on Chiaromonte and the Agnelli Foundation — correspondence, 1972 (Folder 89.1)
      - Translation by Ronald Strom of Chiaromonte article in The New York Review of Books — typescript draft, [1975] (Folder 89.2)
      - Translation by Ronald Strom of Chiaromonte article in The New York Review of Books — typescript variants, [1975] (Folder 89.3)
      - Chiaromonte article in The New York Review of Books — typescript variant [final version?], [1975] (Folder 89.4)
      - Chiaromonte article in The New York Review of Books — galleys and letter from Ron Silvers, 11 November 1974, [1975] (Folder 89.5)
      - Reader correspondence, 1975-1976 (Folder 89.6)
      - McCarthy's thoughts on Chiaromonte's The Paradox of History — typescript notes, 1985; (photocopy) (Folder 89.7)
      - McCarthy's postface for Chiaromonte's The Paradox of History — typescript draft, 1985 (Folder 89.8)
      - McCarthy's postface — publisher's correspondence, 1983 (Folder 89.9)
      - "The Unresigned Man," The New York Review of Books — corrected galley, article proofs, 1985 (Folder 89.10)
      - "The Unresigned Man," The New York Review of Books — printed article, 14 February 1985 (Folder 89.11)
      - Chiaromonte obituaries (Folder 89.12)
      - Theatre book — index and notes (Folder 90.1)
      - Theatre book — photocopies of essays (Folders 90.2 - 90.4)
      - Miscellaneous photocopies (Folders 90.5 - 90.6)
    - Dupee, F. W., The King of Cats (2nd ed., Chicago, 1984)
      - Reference material (Folder 91.1)
      - Typescript variant (several versions) (Folders 91.2 - 91.6)
      - "On F. W. Dupee," 27 October 1983 article in The New York Review of Books — corrected galley proofs (Folder 91.7)
      - "On F. W. Dupee," 27 October 1983 article in The New York Review of Books — printed article (Folder 91.8)
      - Publishers' correspondence regarding preface and article, 1983-1984 (Folder 91.9-.10)
      - Reviews of The King of Cats (Folder 91.11)
- SERIES II. PUBLISHING FILES
  - Agents' Correspondence
    - A.M. Heath (Patience Ross), 1954-1955 (Folder 331.3)
    - A. M. Heath, 1957-1965 (Folders 98.1 - 98.12)
    - A. M. Heath, 1966-1970 (Folders 99.1 - 99.17)
    - A. M. Heath, 1971-1978 (Folders 100.1 - 100.16)
    - A. M. Heath, 1979-1984 (Folders 101.1 - 101.12)
    - A. M. Heath, 1985-1989 (Folder 102.1 -102.12)
    - A.M. Heath, 1985-1989 (Folder 331.4)
    - Brandt and Brandt (Bernice Baumgarten), 1942-1950 (Folder 331.5)
    - Brandt and Brandt (Bernice Baumgarten), 1951-1954 (Folder 331.6)
    - Brandt and Brandt (Bernice Baumgarten), 1955-1959, undated (Folder 331.7)
    - Brandt and Brandt (Bernice Baumgarten), 1942-1957 (Folders 103.1 - 103.9)
    - Brandt and Brandt (Bernice Baumgarten), 1959-1965 (Folders 103.10 - 103.11)
    - Brandt and Brandt (not Baumgarten), 1949, 1958-1971, 1979 (Folders 104.1 - 104.4)
    - LaPautre, Michelle, 1985-1986 (Folder 104.5)
    - La Novelle Agence, 1983-1988 (Folder 104.6)
  - American Publishers' Correspondence
    - Farrar, Straus and Young (Roger W. Straus, Jr.), 1954-1955 (Folder 332.1)
    - Farrar, Straus and Cuddihy (Roger W. Straus, Jr.), 1956-1959 (Folder 332.1)
    - Farrar, Straus, and Cudahy, 1956-1963 (Folders 105.1 - 105.4)
    - Farrar, Straus, and Company, 1964-1965 (Folder 105.5)
    - Farrar, Straus, and Giroux, 1966-1988 (Folders 105.6 - 105.11)
    - Harcourt, Brace and Co. (William Jovanovich), 1950, 1955, 1958 (Folder 332.2)
    - Harcourt, Brace and Co. (Denver Lindley), 1950-1959 (Folder 332.3)
    - Harcourt, Brace, and Co., 1957-1960 (Folders 106.1 - 106.2)
    - Harcourt, Brace, and World, 1961-1967 (Folders 106.3 - 106.13)
    - Harcourt, Brace, and World, 1968-1973 (Folders 107.1 - 107.15)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1974-1978 (Folders 108.1 - 108.15)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1979 - September 1983 (Folders 109.1 - 109.13)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, October 1983 - May 1986 (Folders 110.1 - 110.8)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, June 1986 - December 1988, undated (Folders 111.1 - 111.9)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1988-1989 (Folder 332.4)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich — How I Grew, 1986-1989 (Folders 332.5 - 332.7)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich - Trust, 1988-1990 (Folders 332.8 - 332.9)
    - Alfred A. Knopf Inc. (Alice Quinn, Terry Adams), 1986, 1989 (Folder 333.1)
    - Alfred A. Knopf Inc. (William Cole), 7 January 1954 (Folder 333.2)
    - Avon Books (Bard) (Folder 333.23)
    - American Foundation for Social Justice, 1970 (Folder 112.1)
    - Bobbs-Merrill, 1969 (Folder 112.2)
    - Bollingen Series (John Barrett), 8 January 1947 (Folder 333.3)
    - D. C. Heath, 1987 (Folder 112.3)
    - David McKay Company, 1977 (Folder 112.4)
    - Doubleday, 1969-1983, undated (Folders 112.5 - 112.6)
    - Ecco Press, 1982 (Folder 112.7)
    - Franklin Library, 1976-1983 (Folders 112.8 - 112.10)
    - G. P. Putnam's Sons, 1987-1988 (Folder 112.11)
    - Harper & Brothers (Simon Michael Bessie), 8 October 1953 (Folder 333.5)
    - Harper and Row, 1970-1973 (Folder 112.12)
    - Herder and Herder, 1969 (Folder 112.13)
    - Holt, Rinehart, and Winston, 1972-1984 (Folder 112.14)
    - Jeannette Hopkins [agent], 1974-1976 (Folder 112.15)
    - Houghton Mifflin, 1942-1972 (Folder 112.16)
    - Houghton Mifflin Company (Hardwick Mosely), 1945, undated (Folder 333.6)
    - Houghton Mifflin Company (Robert Linscott), 1942 October 1 (Folder 333.9)
    - Intercultural Publications Inc. (James Laughlin), 1953 (Folder 333.7)
    - Iona College, 1973 (Folder 112.17)
    - Jordan Davies, 1986 (Folder 112.18)
    - Knopf, 1977-1988 (Folder 113.1)
    - Little, Brown, and Co., 1983 (Folder 113.2)
    - MacMillan, 1962-1986 (Folder 113.3)
    - McGraw Hill, 1973 (Folder 113.4)
    - Meridian Books, Inc. (Arthur Cohen), 1957, 1959 (Folder 333.10)
    - NAL (New American Library), 1957-1974 (Folder 113.5)
    - New Directions (James Laughlin), 1988-1989 (Folder 333.24)
    - New Republic Books, 1982-1984 (Folder 113.6)
    - New York Public Library, 1977 (Folder 113.7)
    - North Point Press, 1985 (Folder 113.8)
    - Pantheon, 1946, 1960-1987 (Folder 113.9)
    - Pendle Hill Pamphlets (Peter Docili), 1951 (Folder 333.11)
    - Persea, 1982 (Folder 113.10)
    - Pinnacle Books, 1978 (Folder 113.11)
    - Random House, 1949-1984 (Folder 113.12)
    - Random House Inc. (Robert Linscott), 1949-1952 (Folder 333.8)
    - Reynal & Company, 1962 (Folder 113.13)
    - Reynal & Company (Eugene Reynal), 1956, 1958 (Folder 333.12)
    - Richard Seaver Books, 1976 (Folder 113.14)
    - Seabury Press, 1971 (Folder 113.15)
    - Simon and Schuster, 1971-1982 (Folder 113.16)
    - Spindrift Press, 1974 (Folder 113.17)
    - St. Martin's Press, 1981-1982 (Folder 113.18)
    - Ticknor and Fields, 1988 (Folder 113.19)
    - Time Capsule, Inc., 1982 (Folder 113.20)
    - Times Books, 1983-1984 (Folder 113.21)
    - TCLC, 1987-1988 (Folder 113.22)
    - University of Chicago Press, 1984-1986 (Folder 113.23)
    - University of Missouri Press, 1980 (Folder 113.24)
    - University of Pennsylvania Press, 1983-1984 (Folder 113.25)
    - Urizen Books, 1977 (Folder 113.26)
    - Viking Press, 1971-83 (Folder 113.27)
    - W. W. Norton, 1970-1971 (Folder 113.28)
    - William Morrow, 1969 (Folder 113.29)
    - Yale University Press, 1983 (Folder 113.30)
    - Miscellaneous U.S. publishers, 1957-1986, undated (Folder 113.31)
    - Miscellaneous publishers (Folder 333.13)
  - Foreign Publishers' Correspondence
    - Andre Deutsch, undated (Folder 114.1)
    - Athlone, 1983 (Folder 114.2)
    - "Authors Take Sides on the Falklands,", 1982 (Folder 114.3)
    - Carl Hanser Verlag, 1985 (Folder 114.4)
    - Carl Hanser Verlag, 1988-1989 (Folder 333.14)
    - Collins, 1986 (Folder 114.5)
    - Droemersche Verlagsanstalt, 1969-1982 (Folder 114.6)
    - Éditions Alinea, 1985 (Folder 114.7)
    - Éditions Bernard Grasset, 1971-1984 (Folder 114.8)
    - Éditions Denoel, 1983 (Folder 114.9)
    - Éditions Du Seuil, 1962 (Folder 114.10)
    - Éditions Gallimard, 1969-1980 (Folder 114.11)
    - Éditions Gonthier, 1964-1965 (Folder 114.12)
    - Éditions Jean-Jacques Pauvert, 1967 (Folder 114.13)
    - Éditions Mazarine, 1981 (Folder 114.14)
    - Éditions Robert Laffont, 1971-1979 (Folder 114.15)
    - Éditions Stock, 1963-1983 (Folder 114.16)
    - Editôra Artenova, 1976 (Folder 114.17)
    - Editore Einaudi, 1983 (Folder 114.18)
    - Editorial Lumen, 1971 (Folder 114.19)
    - Editorial Seix Barral, 1964-1966 (Folder 114.20)
    - Europa Verlag, 1972 (Folder 114.21)
    - Giangiacomo Feltrinelli, 1962-1982 (Folder 114.22)
    - Hart-Davis, 1962-1963 (Folder 114.23)
    - Hayakawa, Shobo and Co., 1968-1971 (Folder 114.24)
    - Heinemann, 1957-1967, undated (Folder 114.25)
    - Kooperativa Förbundet Bokförlaget, 1949 (Folder 114.26)
    - Il Mulino, 1983-1985 (Folder 114.27)
    - Jonathan Cape, Ltd., 1966 (Folder 115.1)
    - Lester and Orpen Dennys, 1981 (Folder 115.2)
    - Librairie Arthème Fayard, 1969-1979 (Folder 115.3)
    - Librairie Arthème Fayard, 1986-1988, undated (Folder 115.4)
    - Librairie Ernest Flammarion, 1971 (Folder 115.5)
    - Librairie Plon, 1962-1963 (Folder 115.6)
    - L’Oeil (Rosamond "Peggy" Bernier)1955-1956, undated (Folder 333.16)
    - Luchterhand Verlag, 1981 (Folder 115.7)
    - MacDonald and Co., 1969 (Folder 115.8)
    - Mondadori, 1961-1979 (Folders 115.9 - 115.10)
    - Olympia Press, 1962 (Folder 115.11)
    - Penguin Books, 1973-1984 (Folder 115.12)
    - Peter Owen Ltd., 1965-1974 (Folder 115.13)
    - Piper Verlag, 1961-1986 (Folder 115.14)
    - Polak En Van Gennep, 1965 (Folder 115.15)
    - René Julliard, 1962 (Folder 115.16)
    - Rowohlt Verlag, 1965 (Folder 115.17)
    - R. Piper et Coverlag (Klaus Piper), 22 December 1952 (Folder 333.20)
    - Sellerio editore, 1983-1984 (Folders 115.18 - 115.19)
    - Spóldzielnia Wydawnicza, 1967 (Folder 115.20)
    - Trevi Publishers, 1971-1979 (Folder 115.21)
    - Ugo Guanda, 1961 (Folder 115.22)
    - Ulla Culioli, 1973-1974 (Folder 115.23)
    - Verlag Kiepenheuer and Witsch, 1962 (Folder 115.24)
    - Weidenfeld, 1963-1988 (Folders 116.1 - 116.4)
    - Weidenfeld and Nicholson Limited Publishers (George Weidenfeld), 1957, 1958, 1989 (Folder 333.21)
    - Weidenfeld (Folder 333.22)
    - Wildwood House, 1972 (Folder 116.5)
    - Wydawnictwo Literackie, 1981 (Folder 116.6)
    - Miscellaneous foreign publishers, 1958-1987, undated (Folder 116.7)
  - Publishers' Correspondence: Magazines and Newspapers
    - The American Mercury, (Joseph Breed)1952-1953 (Folder 334.2)
    - The American Poetry Review, 1976-1986 (Folder 117.1)
    - The Atlantic Monthly, 1966-1974, undated (Folder 117.2)
    - Commentary (Norman Podhoretz), 31 January 1956 (Folder 334.3)
    - Commentary (Robert Warshow), 1950, 1952 (Folder 334.4)
    - Der Monat (Melvin Lasky), 1949, 1953 (Folder 333.14)
    - Encounter, 1957-1967 (Folder 117.3)
    - Esquire, 1970-1983, undated (Folder 117.4)
    - Granta, 1989 (Folder 334.24)
    - Harper's Bazaar, 1944, 1952 (Folder 333.4)
    - Harper’s Magazine, 1953, 1959 (Folder 334.5)
    - Harper's Magazine, 1959-1984 (Folder 117.5)
    - Holiday (Harry Sions), 1949-1951 (Folder 334.6)
    - House and Garden with corr. from Hans Hertel, 1983-1985, undated (Folder 117.6)
    - The Kenyon Review (Philip Blair Rice), 1949-1950 (Folder 334.7)
    - Lears, 1989 (Folder 334.30)
    - Libération, 1985 (Folder 117.7)
    - Libération: see also oversize issue with clippings series
    - Libri Paese Seri, 1970 (Folder 117.8)
    - Listener, 1971 (Folder 117.9)
    - London Review of Books, 1981-1985 (Folder 117.10)
    - MD Publications, 1977 (Folder 117.11)
    - Ms., 1976 (Folder 117.12)
    - The New Republic, 1962-1975, undated (Folder 117.13)
    - The New Republic (Gilbert Harrison), 6 December 1956 (Folder 334.9)
    - New Republic (Robert Evett), 7 November 1956 (Folder 334.8)
    - The New Statesman, 1962-1971, undated (Folder 117.14)
    - New York Herald Tribune (Whitelaw Reid), 5 July 1951 (Folder 334.15)
    - New York Post, 1988 (Folder 117.15)
    - New York Post (James Vechsler)., 1949-1952 (Folder 334.16)
    - The New York Review of Books, 1963 - May 1976 (Folders 117.16 - 117.18)
    - The New York Review of Books, June 1976 - Mar 1989, undated (Folders 118.1 - 118.6)
    - New York Review of Books, 1974, 1989 (Folder 334.14)
    - The New York Times, October 1965 - September 1988, undated (Folders 118.7 - 118.8)
    - The New Yorker, 1988-1989 (Folder 334.10)
    - The New Yorker (Leo Hofeller), 1957 (Folder 334.11)
    - The New Yorker (R. Hawley Truax), 1957 (Folder 334.12)
    - New Yorker (Katherine White), 1945-1958, undated (Folder 334.13)
    - The New Yorker, 1953-1987, undated (Folders 119.1 - 119.7)
    - Newsday, 1981-1982 (Folder 119.8)
    - Newsweek, undated (Folder 119.9)
    - Nova, 1969-1970 (Folder 120.1)
    - Le Novel Observateur, 1964-1974 (Folder 120.2)
    - The Observer, London, 1961-1988 (Folders 120.3 - 120.4)
    - The Observer, 3 October 1956 (Folder 334.17)
    - The Paris Review, 1986-1988, undated (Folder 120.5)
    - The Paris Review (Jeanne McCulloch), 1989 September 6 (Folder 333.17)
    - The Partisan Review, 1959-1988, undated (Folders 120.6 - 120.7)
    - The Partisan Review (William Philips, Philip Rahv), 1948-1989 (Folder 334.18)
    - Personality: Symposia on Topical Issues (Werner Wolff), 1950 (Folder 332.10)
    - Playboy, 1959-1971 (Folder 120.8)
    - The Pontiac Press (J. Dickerson), 15 December1958 (Folder 334.19)
    - Preuves (Francois Bondy), 14 January 1954 (Folder 333.18)
    - Punch, 1953-1954 (Folder 333.19)
    - The Reporter, 1949-1956 (Folder 334.20)
    - The Saturday Review, 1972-1973, undated (Folder 120.9)
    - The Saturday Review (Norman Cousins), 23 September 1954 (Folder 334.21)
    - The Southern Review, 1964-1966 (Folder 120.10)
    - The Sunday Telegraph, London, 1961 (Folder 120.11)
    - The Sunday Times, London, 1968-1987, undated (Folder 120.12)
    - "This Week Magazine" (William Nicholas), 31 May 1956 (Folder 334.22)
    - Time/Life, 1966-1972 (Folder 120.13)
    - The Times Herald Record, Middletown, NY, 1988 (Folder 120.14)
    - Town and Country Magazine (Harry Bowll), 21 June 1944 (Folder 334.23)
    - TV Guide, 1982 (Folder 120.15)
    - Vanity Fair, 1984-1986 (Folder 120.16)
    - The Yale Review, 1982-1983 (Folder 120.17)
    - Die Zeit, 1975-1982 (Folder 120.18)
    - Die Zeit, 1988-1989 (Folder 333.22)
    - Miscellaneous magazines, 1960-1983 (Folder 120.19)
    - Miscellaneous magazines and newspapers, 1989 (Folder 334.1)
  - Photographers and Translators' Correspondence
    - Antman, Mark, 1978, undated (Folder 121.1)
    - Beaton, Cecil, undated (Folder 121.2)
    - Freire, Carlos [See folders 195.2 - 195.9]
    - Freund, Gisele, 1977 (Folder 121.3)
    - Kasterine, Dmitri, 1984 (Folder 121.4)
    - McKenna, Rollie, 1969 (Folder 121.5)
    - Morath, Ingeborg [See Miller, Ingeborg, f. 212.5]
    - Nathans, Rhoda, 1974 (Folder 121.6)
    - Salmi, Sylvia [d. 1979, Mexico], 1964-1990 (Folder 121.7)
    - Wise, K. Kelly, 1981-1986 (Folder 121.8)
    - Miscellaneous photographers: (Avedon, Bauer, Hall, Kalter, Nisbert, Raynor, Victor, Wilson), 1971-1987, undated (Folder 121.9)
    - Translators, 1960-1979 (Folder 121.10)
    - Translators, 1987-1988 (Folder 121.11)
    - Translations – Vincent Giroud (Folders 334.25 - 334.26)
    - Translations: McCarthy's MS notes of translations of Ideas and the Novel, Occasional Prose, The Oasis, Feb - Mar 1988 (Folders 121.12 - 121.13)
  - Publishing/Broadcasting Contracts
    - British Broadcasting Corporation (Folder 334.27)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation (Folder 334.28)
    - Farrar, Straus and Cudahy, 1956-1961 (Folder 122.1)
    - Farrar, Straus and Young, 1954 (Folder 122.2)
    - Harcourt, Brace and World, Jan 1950 - July 1972 (Folder 122.3)
    - Harcourt, Brace and World (Folder 122.4)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich (Folder 122.5)
    - The New American Library (NAL), 1962-1963 (Folder 122.6)
    - The New Yorker, 1958-1983 (Folder 122.7)
    - Random House, 1949-1961 (Folder 122.8)
    - University of Maine – MPBN Radio Grant, 13 May 1986 (Folder 334.29)
    - Miscellaneous U.S. publishers, 1940-1965 (Folder 122.9)
    - Miscellaneous U.S. publishers, 1970-1984 (Folder 122.10)
    - Contracts – American (Folder 335.1)
    - Contracts – Foreign (Folder 335.2)
    - Brazilian publishers (Folder 122.11)
    - Canadian publishers (Folder 122.12)
    - Danish publishers (Folder 122.13)
    - Dutch publishers (Folder 122.14)
    - English publishers (Folders 122.15 - 122.16)
    - Finnish, Norwegian and Icelandic publishers (Folder 123.1)
    - French publishers (Folders 123.2 - 123.3)
    - German publishers (Folder 123.4)
    - Hebrew publishers (Folder 123.5)
    - Hungarian publishers (Folder 123.6)
    - Italian publishers (Folders 123.7 - 123.8)
    - Japanese publishers (Folder 123.9)
    - Polish publishers (Folder 123.10)
    - Portuguese publishers (Folder 123.11)
    - Spanish publishers (Folder 123.12)
    - Swedish publishers (Folder 123.13)
    - Swiss publishers (Folder 123.14)
    - Yugoslavia/Rumania publishers (Folder 123.15)
  - Copyright and Permissions
    - U.S. copyrights (Folders 123.16 - 123.17)
    - Foreign copyrights (Folder 123.18)
    - Copyright – various (Folder 335.3)
    - Kathrine Young (Folder 335.4)
    - Permissions (for copyright) (Folder 335.10)
    - Permissions (Folder 335.11)
    - Permissions, 1960-1971 (Folders 125.3 - 125.10)
    - Permissions, 1970-1980 (Folders 126.1 - 126.10)
    - Permissions, 1981-1988, undated (Folders 127.1 - 127.9)
  - Royalties
    - Negative Royalty Statements, 1981 (Folder 335.5)
    - Royalty Statements, 1986-1988 (Folders 335.6 - 335.7)
    - Royalty Statements and Equitable and Deposits, 1982 (Folder 335.9)
    - Royalties — A. M. Heath, 1967, 1972 (Folder 124.1)
    - Royalties — Brandt and Brandt, 1953-1967 (Folder 124.2)
    - Royalties — Droemersche Verlagsanstalt Th. Knaur Nachf, 1967-1972 (Folder 124.3)
    - Royalties — Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1956-1972 (Folder 124.4)
    - Royalties — George Weidenfeld and Nicolson, 1956-1972 (Folder 124.5)
    - Royalties — Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1955-1960 (Folder 124.6)
    - Royalties — Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1966-1972 (Folder 124.7)
    - Royalties — Harcourt Brace Jovanovich (Folder 335.8)
    - Royalties — Western Printing and Lithographing Company, 1955-1959 (Folder 124.8)
    - Royalties — William Heineman, 1950-1972 (Folder 124.9)
    - Royalties — Film version of The Group, 1971-1973 (Folder 124.10)
    - Royalties — Miscellaneous bank documents (Folder 125.1)
    - Royalties — Miscellaneous (Folder 125.2)
- SERIES III. PROFESSIONAL FILES
  - Requests
    - Requests to Interview
      - Ahmed, B., 1982 (Folder 130.1)
      - Belgian Radio and Television (Folmer), 1985-1986 (Folder 130.2)
      - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1953-1954 (Folder 334.27)
      - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1962-1988 (Folders 130.3 - 130.7)
      - British Broadcasting Corporation, 11 April 1989 (Folder 334.28)
      - Bentley, Joanne, 1982 (Folder 130.8)
      - Brook Productions [for British TV discussion: "Art, Repression and Freedom"], 1982-1983 (Folder 130.9)
      - CBS News, 1963-1985 (Folder 130.10)
      - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, 1968-1977 (Folder 130.11)
      - Dabney, Lewis, 1971-1984 (Folder 130.12)
      - Interview with Elizabeth Daniels, Vassar Campus, 1982 (Folder 336.2)
      - Danmarks Radio, 1966-1967 (Folder 130.13)
      - Davis, Linda, 1983 (Folder 130.14)
      - Dick Cavett Show, 1979 (Folder 130.15)
      - Interview with Elzbieta Ettinger (Folder 336.3)
      - Fineberg, Roberta, 1985-1986 (Folder 130.16)
      - Horne, Jed, 1987 (Folder 130.17)
      - Kuehl, Linda [for Commonweal ], 1970-1972 (Folder 130.18)
      - Lees, Richard, 1981-82 (Folder 130.19)
      - MacShane, Frank, 1982 (Folder 130.20)
      - Maine Public Broadcasting, 1982-1987 (Folder 130.21)
      - McGraw-Hill World News, 1968 (Folder 130.22)
      - Moore, Geoffrey, 1982 (Folder 130.23)
      - NBC-TV, 1966 (Folder 130.24)
      - NRC Handelsblad, 1973-1985 (Folder 130.25)
      - Niebuhr, Elisabeth, 1961 (Folder 130.26)
      - Oltmans, Willem (A. W. Bruna and Zoons), 1972-1973 (Folder 130.27)
      - Orchard, P. B., 1985-1986 (Folder 130.28)
      - Paris Metro, 1977-1978 (Folder 130.29)
      - Sender Freies Berlin, 1972 (Folder 130.30)
      - Underwood, Thomas A., 1987 (Folder 131.1)
      - Village Voice, 1974-1975 (Folder 131.2)
      - Waldron, Ann, 1985 (Folder 131.3)
      - Wetzsteon, Ross, 1986-1988 (Folder 131.4)
      - Wineapple, Brenda, 1986-1987 (Folder 131.5)
      - Women's Wear Daily, 1970-1987 (Folder 131.6)
      - Wreszin, Michael, 1986-1988 (Folders 131.7 - 131.8)
      - Yale University (correspondence with transcript of interview), 1958 (Folder 131.9)
      - Miscellaneous requests to interview, 1961-1978 (Folders 131.10 - 131.18)
      - Miscellaneous requests to interview, 1979-1988, undated (Folders 132.1 - 132.11)
      - Miscellaneous requests for interview, 1989 (Folder 336.1)
    - Interview Texts and Transcripts
      - "Academic Life in the U.S. Today" — typescript of recorded talk by McCarthy, 20 June 1952 (Folder 133.1)
      - "Talking of Books," BBC program — typescript, 1953 (Folder 133.2)
      - "A Talk with Mary McCarthy," Nowa Cultura (Poland) by Cecylia Wojewoda — English translation and Polish article, 30 June 1960 (Folder 133.3)
      - Interview texts, (3) (Folder 133.4)
      - "Domande à Mary McCarthy," TV interview — typescript and note, February 1964 (Folder 133.5)